

Vlad Mataoanu

Data Scientist

About me

I am a Data Scientist with 5 years of experience.

I help companies around the world make informed business decisions and predict the future based on their data.

Stack

- · Python: skit-learn, tensorflow, PySpark, pandas, numpy
- Azure ML
- PowerBI, Dax, MySQL
- SSIS, ETL

Find out more

linkedin.com/in/vlad-mataoanu/ github.com/vmatao

Contact information

vlad.mataoanu@gmail.com +40 754 377 876 Bucharest, Romania

Languages

English

Full professional proficiency

Danish

Limited working profficiency

Romanian

Native

Work Experience



Data Scientist

Fiskars Group | Jan 2023 - currently

· Used ML algorithms for pricing optimization and finding the frequently bought together items in the retail industry

2operate Data Scientist

2operate | Dec 2018 - Jan 2023

- · Used Python for ML unsupervised cluster analysis and at different stages of data analysis and preparation
- · Been a part of the ETL process and data warehousing (MySQL)
- · Worked on various BI projects involving customers from the telecommunication industry and created BI reports for development and promotional purposes



Assistant Business Intelligence Specialist

Talenthub.io | Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

 Worked on various BI projects (built mainly in PowerBI and data studio) and created CRM-based insights

Education

Master of Science (MSc) in Computer Science **Aalborg University**

• Decoding EEG data into motor intention movements using a CNN-based spatial-temporal algorithm. It could be used to "mind control" an exoskeleton.

Professional Bachelor Of Software Development + AP University College of Northern Denmark

• Elective semester in Big Data: Business Intelligence & Python